<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://blog.revival.us.kg</id>
    <title>Revival</title>
    <updated>2026-01-24T00:38:36.371Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <author>
        <name>Blaze the Star</name>
        <email>startheblaze@gmail.com</email>
        <uri>https://blog.revival.us.kg</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://blog.revival.us.kg"/>
    <subtitle>DESC</subtitle>
    <logo>https://blog.revival.us.kg/img/logo.png</logo>
    <icon>https://blog.revival.us.kg/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>© 2026 Blaze the Star</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revival Ch.1]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/1</id>
        <link href="https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/1"/>
        <updated>2025-12-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="draggedfromthedeep">Dragged From the Deep</h3>
<p>Joseph surfaced from sleep like he was dragged up through murky water—slow, groggy, barely conscious of the world he was returning to.<br />
H...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="draggedfromthedeep">Dragged From the Deep</h3>
<p>Joseph surfaced from sleep like he was dragged up through murky water—slow, groggy, barely conscious of the world he was returning to.<br />
He shifted beneath his covers, expecting the soft cocoon of blankets and the hum of familiar warmth.  </p>
<p>Instead, the ground beneath his back was uneven and gritty with dirt.<br />
A chill threaded through the air, sharp as claws against his skin.  </p>
<p>He inhaled on instinct, and the smells hit him all at once—<br />
raw earth,<br />
cool and murky with the smell of fallen leaves,<br />
wood-smoke drifting from some unseen fire,<br />
and other wild scents he had no names for.  </p>
<p>Each one was startlingly overwhelming, the kind of jarring strength that made his mind reel at how sharp everything suddenly seemed.  </p>
<p>Unfamiliar voices pressed around him—quick, startled, overlapping as they argued in urgent hisses and low growls.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“—shouldn’t’ve been lyin’ there—”  </p>
  <p>“—a forest, of all places—”  </p>
  <p>“—anybody unconscious out here means trouble for someone—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>There was an edge beneath the concern.<br />
Not fear—responsibility.  </p>
<p>Joseph heard it without recognizing why.  </p>
<p>These people were talking like professionals dealing with a problem they couldn’t afford to mishandle.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s eyelids fluttered open.<br />
Light stabbed into them.<br />
The sun felt too bright, too close.<br />
He winced and squeezed them shut again.  </p>
<p>A sudden shift rippled through the figures around him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“He’s wakin’,” someone murmured.  </p>
  <p>“Easy now—don’t spook.” another added.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>A small voice piped up beside him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Here, drink—or at least wet your face.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wooden scraping followed.<br />
Joseph blinked until shapes stopped doubling.  </p>
<h3 id="strangerinthewater">Stranger in the Water</h3>
<p>A round bowl of water stood inches from his nose.  </p>
<p>He lifted his head slowly, the blanket shifting down as he peered in — he paused.<br />
He expected to see his reflection, but it didn't look right.  </p>
<p>The water shimmered the image of a slim snout, large pointed ears, and fluff pointing out from his cheeks.  </p>
<p>A fox.  </p>
<p>He stared a moment too long, waiting for the reflection to correct itself.  </p>
<p>It didn't.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Huh,” his voice low, almost dead sounding.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He lifting a hand toward his reflection—except his hand wasn’t a hand.<br />
A paw, slim and furred, touched the water’s surface, sending ripples across the creature’s face.  </p>
<p>He paused, then poked his ear.<br />
It twitched. Reflexively.  </p>
<p>His tired brain glowed with sudden childlike delight.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Heh… that’s kinda neat,” he whispered to himself.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everything still felt hazy, the world soft at the edges—dreamlike.<br />
Maybe that’s all this was.  </p>
<p>He brushed his ear once more, pleased when it moved on it's own.  </p>
<p>Voices sounded around him—tight, uncomfortable.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Ain’t the reaction I expected,” a rough voice muttered, edged with annoyance under the concern.  </p>
  <p>“Folk found knocked out in Chloros don’t wake smilin’,” another added. Not accusing—just wary.  </p>
  <p>“Could be he hit his head,” the smallest voice whispered uncertain—more like repeating what he’d heard the grown-ups say.<br />
  “Or got dosed. He ain’t actin’ right.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="circleofeyes">Circle of Eyes</h3>
<p>Joseph tore his gaze from the water and found them.  </p>
<p>They surrounded him—upright animals in simple tunics and rough-weave trousers, fabrics the color of soil and bark, worn soft by years of labor.<br />
No ornament. No flourish. Just usefulness.<br />
And every gaze fixed on him was sharp, professional, evaluating.  </p>
<p>One of them—a young otter— shifted on his paws, tension flickering—then his face lit up with pride, as if remembering his moment to shine.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Name’s Chatter! I found ya! Well, Snout did the sniffin’, sure, but I laid eyes on ya first."<br />
  "That’s gotta be worth something.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>A coyote sat on her haunches—lean, dusk-colored, with watchful amber eyes—eased forward.<br />
Her gaze swept him with slow precision, taking him in, but she said nothing.  </p>
<p>Beside her towered a bobcat—broad-shouldered, arms crossed, looking like he’d skipped sleep and preferred it that way.<br />
His tail flicked once with irritation.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Name's Fight,” he grunted, by way of introduction.<br />
  “And before ya ask: we ain’t here to coddle ya."<br />
  "Rules o’ the trade say we haul in anything suspicious we come across."<br />
  "You top that list, friend.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s playful disbelief faltered.<br />
<em>Suspicious? Rules of the trade?</em><br />
<em>Dreams don’t come with laws…</em><br />
<em>Well… maybe nightmares would.</em>  </p>
<p>Fight leaned in slightly, the weight of a man who’d asked this question a hundred rough mornings before.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“So. Mind tellin’ us why you were passed out in the middle of the forest? And without a stitch on ya?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="weightofeyes">Weight of Eyes</h3>
<p>Joseph blinked, startled.  </p>
<p>His gaze darted down.<br />
The blanket had slipped to his shoulders—revealing he wore absolutely nothing underneath.<br />
He yanked it back up to his neck so fast it snapped.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Why am I not wearing clothes!?” he yelped, clutching the cover around himself.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight shrugged, unimpressed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Great. Another mystery.”<br />
  “You’re either the poor fool somethin’ happened to… or the fool who did somethin’ to himself.”<br />
  “Either way, we gotta figure it out.”  </p>
  <p>“Fight,” the coyote said quietly—just a soft nudge of restraint, enough to reel him back from his edge.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph tried to sit up, embarrassment prickling across him.<br />
There were too many eyes on him. He was too exposed.  </p>
<p>A strange, instinctive pressure pushed at him—<em>stand up, get steady, look like you belong</em>—and layered beneath that, a very human desire not to look helpless, naked, or afraid.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“No, I-I’m fine,” he muttered.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Whether he said it to convince them or himself, he wasn’t sure.<br />
Either way, he braced and tried to rise.  </p>
<p>His legs trembled at once.  </p>
<p>The angles were wrong—center of gravity skewed, feet shaped nothing like feet, toes missing entirely where he expected them, leaving him unable to plant or balance.<br />
For a moment he hung there in an awkward half-stand—  </p>
<p>—and then his weight tipped forward uncontrollably as his unfamiliar limbs buckled beneath him.  </p>
<p>Joseph hit the dirt with a soft thump—more humiliating than painful.<br />
He stayed where he landed, face still in the dirt.  </p>
<h3 id="injuredpride">Injured Pride</h3>
<p>No one rushed forward.<br />
They didn’t look shocked—just concerned in the practical, professional way of people who’d seen every kind of injury, but not this kind of behavior.  </p>
<p>Chatter’s whiskers drooped.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Maybe he <em>is</em> hurt…”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph let out a long, unmistakably exasperated sigh—into the dirt.<br />
Not because he was hurt.<br />
Because they <em>believed</em> he was.  </p>
<p>Snout edged closer, posture low, a paw stretched out open.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Easy now. Don’t force yourself. Just tell us straight—what part of you’s hurtin’? Legs? Head? Chest?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph pushed one elbow under himself, lifted his muzzle just enough to speak, then let the rest of him remain slumped.  </p>
<p>His voice came out flat, edged with frustration he barely bothered to hide.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“<em>Everything</em> feels wrong.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout blinked, taken aback—not by the attitude, but by the honesty.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Fight grunted. “That ain’t helpful.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph didn’t respond.  </p>
<p>He refused to defend himself.<br />
Refused to argue.<br />
Let them think whatever they wanted—because explaining himself never changed anything.  </p>
<p>Snout tried again, gentler.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“…Wrong how?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph hesitated.  </p>
<p>He didn’t know where to start.<br />
How to explain toes that didn’t exist, a body that moved wrong—that was shaped weird.  </p>
<p>They wouldn’t believe him anyway.  </p>
<p>But Snout waited without pressing.<br />
And Fight—arms crossed, eyes squinting as if trying to read him—held back the next accusation.<br />
Even Chatter looked more worried than curious.  </p>
<p>They weren’t guessing anymore.<br />
They were trying to <em>understand</em>.  </p>
<p>Joseph sighed again—this time quieter, resigned.  </p>
<p>He turned his head enough to meet their eyes.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“…I’m not hurt,” he said slowly.<br />
  “I’m…” He scoffed, eyes squeezing shut.<br />
  “I don’t know how to explain it.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The coyote leaned closer, tone gentler than before.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“We’re tryin’ to understand. Just give us somethin’ to go on.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>For a heartbeat, Joseph considered staying silent—letting them be wrong, letting them draw their own conclusions.<br />
It would be easier.  </p>
<p>It always was.  </p>
<p>Their eyes were on him — not accusing, not dismissing — watching.<br />
And that made it harder to hide.  </p>
<p>So he breathed once, heavy.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I’m human.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="identity">Identity</h3>
<p>They exchanged small, puzzled looks—quiet, shared uncertainty.  </p>
<p>Chatter blinked.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“A… what now?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight’s posture went stiff, expression flattening into something halfway between dread and annoyance.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Right, Alright… he’s crazy.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s breath caught.<br />
Whatever fragile thread of dignity he’d been holding onto snapped, and he let himself slump back down into the dirt—<br />
half from exhaustion, half to avoid meeting anyone’s eyes.  </p>
<p>Snout snapped her gaze toward him, ears pinning back.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Fight. Mind yer tongue.”  </p>
  <p>“What? I’m just sayin’ what we’re all thinkin’,” Fight grumbled, though he took a half-step back as if trying to remove himself from the absurdity.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout shot him a warning look that could’ve cut bark.  </p>
<p>Fight lifted his paws in surrender.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Fine. Fine. Look—<strong>Eli</strong> needs to deal with this.”<br />
  “You two stay here. Don’t let him try standin’ again.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>With a final huff, the bobcat turned and strode into the trees, tail flicking in frazzled irritation.  </p>
<p>Snout and Chatter hovered near Joseph, unsure if they should speak or stay silent.<br />
Joseph didn’t lift his head.<br />
His humiliation burned hotter than the failed attempt to stand.  </p>
<p>This was a dream. It had to be.<br />
If it were, he could just… <strong>fly away</strong> from this whole mess.<br />
Flex his mind, break the scene, wake up.  </p>
<p>But he couldn’t do any of that.  </p>
<p>The world held him in place—too solid, too vivid. Impossible.  </p>
<p>The woods behind them shifted—brush parting beneath heavy, deliberate steps.  </p>
<p>Snout and Chatter turned to see Fight had returned—with another figure at his side.  </p>
<p>Joseph lifted his head—just enough to see.<br />
And froze.  </p>
<h3 id="wolfsmeasure">Wolf’s Measure</h3>
<p>A red wolf stepped into view—tall as a nightmare, broad-shouldered and long-limbed.<br />
And there was Joseph, crumpled in the dirt, a small pale fox barely larger than a heap of clothes.<br />
The size difference was obscene — like a house beside a toppled broom.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s first instinct was pure, primal awe.  </p>
<p>The wolf’s amber eyes swept the scene—Joseph on the ground, Snout sat beside him, Chatter half-hidden behind her.  </p>
<p>His expression was calm, but not warm—distant, reading, calculating what mattered and what didn’t.  </p>
<p>His eyes landed on Joseph, small and blanketed, curled in the dirt.  </p>
<p>His expression <strong>shifted.</strong> Barely.<br />
A tighten at the eyes.<br />
A momentary inhale.<br />
A recognition he forced back down in less than a heartbeat.  </p>
<p>Snout noticed. Her ears tipped warily.  </p>
<p>Fight cleared his throat.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“This the one makin’ trouble. Told you already—says he’s… well.” He flicked a paw toward Joseph.<br />
  “He's crazy.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout snapped,  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Fight—mind your manners.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli didn’t respond to either of them.<br />
His gaze stayed on Joseph—steady, evaluating.<br />
Almost… searching.  </p>
<p>Joseph felt it.<br />
Even through the blanket, even with his face half in the dirt.<br />
Someone was seeing him—not the fox body, not the assumed injuries, but <em>him</em>.  </p>
<p>Eli stepped closer. Slowly. Carefully.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re the one callin’ yourself ‘human’?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>His tone wasn’t mocking.<br />
Or skeptical.<br />
Or angry.  </p>
<p>It was controlled. Too controlled.  </p>
<p>Joseph looked up, eyes tired, ears angled flat.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Y-Yeah,” he said softly. “That's me.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>For a split second—quick as a heartbeat—Eli’s expression changed.<br />
Recognition.<br />
Understanding deeper than Snout or Chatter could have shown.  </p>
<p>Then the mask returned, smooth and unreadable.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“All right,” Eli said quietly.<br />
  “Then we start simple.”<br />
  “What d’ya need right now? Water? Shade? Space?"<br />
  "Or just… time?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph stared at him.<br />
Everything around him still felt impossible.  </p>
<p>He croaked out the only honest thing he could manage.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I-I… I don’t know.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli nodded once, slow and accepting—no judgment, no impatience.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Then we take it one breath at a time.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="recognition">Recognition</h3>
<p>Even Snout blinked at that, thrown off by the gentleness.  </p>
<p>Chatter peeked out.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“So… is he crazy?” he whispered—too loudly.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli’s ear flicked, but his gaze stayed on Joseph.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“No,” he said, simply.<br />
  Then he added, quieter, meant only for Joseph:<br />
  “Just lost.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph wasn’t sure how long he lay there staring up at Eli, trying to make sense of a world that refused to make sense back.<br />
But at last, Eli shifted his weight closer.  </p>
<p>He lowered onto his haunches and extended a paw—steady, patient.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Come on,” Eli said. “Let’s get you on your feet.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph hesitated.<br />
Not because he didn’t want the help, but because Eli’s paw looked huge enough to wrap around his whole forearm.<br />
Still… he dug an arm from the cover and placed the paw in Eli’s.  </p>
<p>Eli closed his grip carefully—gentle, deliberate—and pulled him upright.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s legs trembled instantly.<br />
Every tiny shift sent his body swaying like a newborn deer.  </p>
<h3 id="shakenfoundations">Shaken Foundations</h3>
<p>He stepped wrong and lurched—Eli caught him with one arm before he could fall again.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Easy now,” Eli murmured.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph swallowed hard, heat crawling up his ears—not from pain, but humiliation.  </p>
<p><em>They think I’m helpless.</em><br />
And now Eli—this enormous, impossible, self-contained wolf—was holding him up like a child.  </p>
<p>Snout stepped closer, eyes narrowed in concern.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Eli, he can barely stand. We should take him slow—”  </p>
  <p>“We will,” Eli said.<br />
  “But we’re not leaving him here.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight pushed out a sigh, arms crossed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“So what’s the plan? We cart him back and hope he don’t fall apart on the trail?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli glanced at him, something unreadable in his eyes.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“No. We prepare.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>There was an authority in his tone—not sharp, but final. The shift made both Fight and Snout straighten without thinking.  </p>
<p>Eli looked between them.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Get him clothes. Something light, until we can measure him proper.”<br />
  “And make sure our provisions are counted for one more.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout blinked.  </p>
<p>Fight’s tail flicked in surprise.  </p>
<p>Chatter beamed.  </p>
<p>Joseph, however, felt the words hit him like a stone to the chest.  </p>
<p><strong>One more.</strong><br />
As if he belonged with them.<br />
As if he were being welcomed into something he wasn’t sure he had a place in.  </p>
<p>His stomach knotted. He didn’t deserve it.<br />
Not their help.<br />
Not their resources.<br />
Not their trust.  </p>
<p>He’d already been trouble the very moment they’d found him—<br />
confusion,<br />
wasted time,<br />
frustration for Fight,<br />
worry for Snout.  </p>
<p>And now Eli wanted to give him more.  </p>
<p>He stared at the ground, ears flattening.  </p>
<p><em>They don’t know me.</em><br />
<em>They don’t owe me anything.</em><br />
<em>I shouldn’t be taking from them.</em>  </p>
<p>But Eli never took his steadying arm away.<br />
Little by little, Joseph realized he was standing on his own—not well, but better—his legs shaking less with each breath.<br />
The small victory only sharpened the guilt in his chest.<br />
Eli seemed to sense it, his presence steady beside him.  </p>
<h3 id="takenin">Taken In</h3>
<p>Fight broke the moment with a grumble.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re intendin’ on bringin’ him with us?”  </p>
  <p>“Yes,” Eli said simply.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout exchanged a glance with Fight—more curious than resistant now.  </p>
<p>Fight muttered something under his breath, but he didn’t argue.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Fine,” he said.<br />
  “Clothes. Provisions. I’ll handle it.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout gave Joseph a gentler look—still cautious, but softer.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“We’ll be quick.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The two of them headed back toward camp, Chatter scampering behind them with eager, erratic enthusiasm.  </p>
<p>And then it was just Joseph and Eli.  </p>
<p>The wind carried earthy lake-scent and cedar.  </p>
<p>Joseph leaned slightly against Eli’s arm because he had no choice—but the wolf didn’t treat it like a burden.  </p>
<p>After a long silence, Eli spoke—not unkindly.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You think you’re imposing.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph blinked, startled.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I-I… I Just—”<br />
  He struggled for words.<br />
  “You don’t have to waste your supplies on me. I-I don’t even know if I belong here.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli looked down at him—towering, unreadable, unshaken.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re lost,” he said. “That’s enough reason.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph opened his mouth, closed it again.  </p>
<p>Eli eased his grip, letting Joseph try to stand a little more on his own.<br />
Joseph’s legs quivered like reeds in water—but he stayed upright. Barely.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“We’ll take this at yer pace,” Eli said. “No debts. No owing.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph stared at him, overwhelmed and too tired to hide it.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Why?” he whispered.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli’s gaze softened—fractionally.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Because someone once did the same for me.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Before Joseph could ask what that meant, Snout’s voice echoed from the treeline:  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Got clothes! And rations!”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter tripped over a branch in his excitement.  </p>
<p>Fight’s irritated snarl followed.  </p>
<p>Eli’s arm pressed lightly to Joseph’s back.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Let’s get you ready,” he said.<br />
  “Then we head home.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Home.<br />
The word lodged somewhere deep in Joseph’s chest—strange, unwelcome, and yearning all at once.  </p>
<p>And with that, Joseph stepped—shaking, bewildered—into a life that had already begun moving around him.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Blaze the Star</name>
            <email>startheblaze@gmail.com</email>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revival Ch.2]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/2</id>
        <link href="https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/2"/>
        <updated>2025-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="thelongwalk">The Long Walk</h3>
<p>The morning opened wide around them—an autumn field under a bright, cold sun.<br />
The air carried a crisp, metallic bite that slipped clean through fur and...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="thelongwalk">The Long Walk</h3>
<p>The morning opened wide around them—an autumn field under a bright, cold sun.<br />
The air carried a crisp, metallic bite that slipped clean through fur and cloth.<br />
Grass bowed in the wind, dull golds and browns rolling in slow waves beneath a ridge of trees holding the last of their faded rusts and dry greens.<br />
A few stood bare already, branches thin and skeletal.<br />
Cedar drifted faintly on each passing breeze.  </p>
<p>Wooden wheels clattered along the dirt path.<br />
Eli hauled the lead cart by its long handles, leaning half his weight into each step.<br />
The red wolf’s broad shoulders and long, steady gait made the effort look easy.<br />
Fight followed with the second, paws braced on the grips, tail flicking at every rock that rattled the load.  </p>
<p>Joseph came last with Snout and Chatter—not that he was deliberately falling behind.<br />
His legs simply refused to behave.<br />
Even after a night of “practice,” every step on fox paws felt like learning to walk all over again.<br />
Balance wobbled.<br />
Toes weren’t where he expected them to be.<br />
And the ground always seemed to tilt unexpectedly.  </p>
<p>He leaned heavily on the walking stick he found on the way.<br />
The clothes they’d given him—simple trousers tied at the ankle and a loose tunic—helped him feel less exposed, but the autumn wind still cut through them. So he still kept the blanket wrapped around his shoulders, held tight like a shield.  </p>
<p>Chatter had no such slow pace.<br />
The otter skittered from one side of the path to the other, talking almost faster than he breathed.  </p>
<h3 id="questions">Questions</h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>“So when you said you didn’t have fur—none?”<br />
  “Not even on your arms? Or tail—wait, you didn’t have a tail either, right?”<br />
  “Didn’t that feel weird?”<br />
  “Also, did bein’ outside feel cold all the time?”<br />
  “Like, did you feel naked not havin’ any fur? And how’d you—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph opened his mouth to answer one of those questions—he wasn’t sure which—but Chatter had already launched into the next.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“—and is bein’ tall better? Or is bein’ small better?”<br />
  “Oh! What’s it like havin’—y’know—flat ears?”<br />
  “Do they even move?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph blinked, processing maybe half of that.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Uh—well—sorta—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter leaned closer, eyes glowing with fascination, steps bouncing like he had springs in his ankles.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Snout cut in with a sharp, “Chatter. Ease up.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter skidded to a halt, ears folding.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh. …Right.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then he darted ahead to trail behind Fight instead.  </p>
<p>The quiet that followed wrapped Joseph like much-needed warmth.  </p>
<p>Snout slowed her steps to match his.<br />
The coyote’s lean frame moved with an easy, rangy stride, her ears swiveling at every sound in the treeline.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You keepin’ up?” she asked.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded, though he wasn’t sure it was true.<br />
Snout kept pace beside him, her eyes still scanning the treeline now and again.  </p>
<p>It made him realize he had no idea where they were even headed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Where… are we going, anyway?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout glanced down the road.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Flint Water. Small city couple hours ahead. It’s where we’re based.”  </p>
  <p>“Like… home?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>She shrugged one shoulder.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Closest thing to it. We do most o’ our work outta there.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph considered that, tapping the stick lightly against the ground as he walked.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What kind of work?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout blew out a slow breath, as if choosing her words.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“We’re a sort o’ contracted law-enforcers. Keep the peace. Track down criminals.”<br />
  “Sometimes take bounties if they line up with our route.”<br />
  “Folks call on us when somethin’ goes wrong.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph blinked, surprised.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Like… sheriffs?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout made a so-so motion with her paw.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Somethin’ like that. Just… less paperwork.”<br />
  “We go where the work leads us.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="kin">Kin</h3>
<p>They walked a bit more after that, the explanation settling quietly between them.  </p>
<p>Only then did Snout speak again.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You got any kin where you’re from?”  </p>
  <p>“Yeah. My parents and two siblings. A brother and a sister.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout’s voice softened.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You close with ’em?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>A small smile tugged at him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Yeah. I… I love my family.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout hummed, thoughtful.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Then you must miss ’em somethin’ fierce.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph opened his mouth—then hesitated.  </p>
<p>He pictured their faces — his mother's smile, his dad's steady voice—but nothing.  </p>
<p>He searched for the feeling he was supposed to have—an ache, a longing, some sharp tug in the chest.<br />
But all he found was a distant fog.<br />
A sense he <em>should</em> miss them.<br />
Nothing more.  </p>
<p>Guilt crawled up his throat.  </p>
<p><em>What kind of person doesn’t miss his family?</em><br />
<em>Do I even care about them?</em><br />
<em>What’s wrong with me?</em>  </p>
<p>His next step caught the edge of a rut. His shaky legs tangled, and before he could correct himself, the world tilted sideways.  </p>
<p>He squeaked and hit the ground with a soft oof—startled, but not hurt.  </p>
<p>Snout was at his side in a heartbeat.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Easy. You alright?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph pushed himself upright, leaning hard on the stick.<br />
His ears burned, more embarrassed by the sound he made than the fall.<br />
His legs trembled once, then settled.  </p>
<h3 id="confession">Confession</h3>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I’m okay,” he said quietly—more reflex than truth.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout hovered a second longer, making sure he wasn’t about to topple again, then stepped back to give him space.  </p>
<p>They resumed walking, and for a moment Joseph considered dropping the conversation, but the weight in his chest didn’t lift.  </p>
<p>Finally, he exhaled.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I do love them my family. I know I do. But…”<br />
  He swallowed, searching for the shape of a feeling that wasn’t there.<br />
  “I don't know… I just don't miss them as much as… as much as I'd expect to.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout’s ears twitched back—not unkindly, just uncertain.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Well,” she said after a moment,<br />
  “shock can make folk feel strange.”<br />
  Her tone was careful, as if she were afraid of stepping wrong.<br />
  “Confusion. Numbness. Forgettin’ things you oughta remember. Happens sometimes.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded, but her words didn’t reach the place in him that needed reaching.  </p>
<p>Snout glanced at him again, brow furrowed like she wished she had something better to offer.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’ll… sort it out. I reckon.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>It wasn’t comforting. Not even close.  </p>
<p>But it was the best she had, and somehow that made it gentler.  </p>
<p>Joseph tightened his grip on the stick, eyes low.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I hope so,” he said.  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="fadinglight">Fading Light</h3>
<p>The hours slipped by in a slow, uneven rhythm—quiet footfalls, the steady creak of carts, the whisper of wind through brittle fall grass.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Should’ve hit Flint Water before sundown,”<br />
  The bobcat's low growl sat just beneath the words.<br />
  “If we weren’t slowin’ for him, we’d be there already.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout shot Fight a warning look, and his ears tilted back—not in apology, but in reluctant quiet.</p>
<p>Joseph’s ears dipped.<br />
He tried to lengthen his stride, to match the others—but the moment he pushed himself, his legs wobbled and he fell right back into the same weary pace.  </p>
<p>The forest thinned as they walked, trees stretching sparse and bare like fingers clawing at a pale afternoon sky.<br />
The world around them seemed drained of color, washed in soft browns and greys, as if even nature were tired.  </p>
<p>Chatter talked now and then, small stories about nothing, but he always trailed off when Joseph didn’t answer.<br />
Snout stayed close, glancing at Joseph every so often to check that he still walked steady.<br />
Eli led the way with a quiet, purposeful stride, Fight trailing behind like a shadow of impatience.  </p>
<p>Joseph felt the day gathering in his muscles—small aches along his back and sides, a stiffness he hadn’t expected.<br />
What puzzled him most was how easily the others managed it, their strides steady while his own grew heavier with each mile.<br />
He found himself leaning on it more and more—not for balance, but just to keep upright.  </p>
<p>By the time they crested a gentle rise and reached a flattened stretch of road, twilight had already slipped into full night.<br />
The sky opened above them—broad, quiet, studded with a thousand fragile stars.  </p>
<p>They kept moving even after darkness fully settled, their shapes drifting lanternless along the path.<br />
Only the stars and a thin crescent moon lit their way, washing the road in pale silver and sharpening the bite of the cold.<br />
Their breaths rose in soft clouds as they walked, steps slower now, quieter—less from caution than fatigue.  </p>
<p>After another long while, the land began to change.<br />
Faint fence posts appeared along the roadside—old, leaning, some half-buried in grass.<br />
Then the darker smudges of distant rooftops gathered on the horizon, scattered like a quiet promise: the far-most outskirts of Flint Water.  </p>
<p>Still they pressed on a little farther, closing the distance until the silhouettes of barns and watch-lamps were near enough to make out their shapes, though not their details.<br />
Close enough to walk to in the morning.<br />
Close enough to work from.<br />
But far enough to remain unseen.  </p>
<p>Only then did Eli call a halt, lifting one hand for the others to stop. He guided them toward a patch of open ground just off the road where the grass sloped gently and the wind broke against a line of scrub pines.  </p>
<h3 id="finalhalt">Final Halt</h3>
<p>Without a word, Eli, Snout, and Fight began unloading the carts and setting up camp.<br />
They worked with practiced coordination—shaking out tents, driving stakes, gathering what dry sticks and brittle brush they could find.<br />
Soon, the clearing glowed with the first flicker of a small, tight fire.  </p>
<p>Joseph hovered close by while the others unpacked the carts, unsure where to stand, unsure how to be useful.<br />
He stepped forward when Eli hauled out the tent canvas, and again when Snout dragged over the wooden stakes, moving more from obligation than strength.  </p>
<p>A faint, uneven tremor kept running through him deep through his middle—his lower back and the muscles along his sides struggling to keep him upright.<br />
The strain climbed into his shoulders from all the bracing. Even lifting his stick felt like effort.  </p>
<p>Snout noticed first.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Hold up, fox. You’re shiverin’ out your bones. Go sit by the fire.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph opened his mouth to argue—though he had nothing to argue with.<br />
He hadn’t even touched anything yet.  </p>
<p>Before he could speak, Eli chimed in without looking up from the ropes he was sorting:  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“She’s right. You’re spent. Let your legs quit before the rest of you does.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>There was no bite in it—just blunt practicality.  </p>
<p>Joseph hesitated. Relief flickered through him, soft and shameful.<br />
He nodded once and stepped back.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Yeah, ok.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter darted in next, bright-eyed and ready to fill the gap Joseph left.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I can get the stakes! Or the brush—no, the stakes—wait, which one d’you want first?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight shifted aside to make room, tail twitching but not dismissive.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Just—keep to the right side. And don’t trip me.”  </p>
  <p>“Right side! Got it!”<br />
  Chatter chirped—already scooting to the wrong side before correcting himself mid-step.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout huffed, but there was the flicker of a fond smile in it.  </p>
<h3 id="sidelines">Sidelines</h3>
<p>Joseph watched them for a moment longer, the scene blurring faintly at the edges.<br />
Guilt tugged at him—sitting while they worked—but so did a strange, heavy relief.<br />
His muscles ached all the way down into the joints, an exhausted hum that spread the moment he stopped moving.  </p>
<p>He drifted to the fire and sank to his haunches beside the low ring of stones.<br />
The heat touched only the front of his face, leaving his back cold beneath the blanket.  </p>
<p>They didn’t need him.<br />
He wasn’t helping.<br />
But sitting still felt like collapsing, like the moment he stopped moving everything inside him sagged at once.  </p>
<p>He lingered there a minute or two, staring at the shifting silhouettes of the others as they raised tents and sorted gear.<br />
Each rope hauled, each stake hammered, each quiet exchange of instructions twisted inside him.<br />
He tried to watch.<br />
Tried to stay part of it.<br />
But the guilt only thickened, hot and painful behind his ribs.  </p>
<p>He couldn’t sit here and do nothing while they worked—not watch it happen.  </p>
<p>Joseph pushed himself up again, the blanket slipping around his shoulders.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I… think I’m gonna step away for a bit.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>No one looked up.<br />
Chatter was talking, Fight was adjusting a crossbeam, Snout was checking the tent’s stability, and Eli was still tying rope with practiced efficiency.  </p>
<p>Joseph turned on stiff legs and limped toward the darker edge of the clearing until the fire’s glow thinned into nothing more than a warm, wavering smear behind him.  </p>
<h3 id="communion">Communion</h3>
<p>He walked until the sounds of camp faded, until he could breathe without feeling watched.  </p>
<p>He settled onto the cold ground, the chill of it reaching up through the thin fur along his legs.<br />
The breeze cut through the clearing in small biting drifts, and he pulled the blanket close until he was almost swallowed in it.  </p>
<p>The world was still.<br />
Bare branches swayed gently overhead.<br />
Grass rustled softly.<br />
The stars seemed sharper out here, unmarred by smoke or camp-talk.  </p>
<p>Despite the barren season, the land held a quiet, worn beauty.<br />
Subtle. Honest.  </p>
<p>It brought a familiar ache into his chest—a reminder of creation, of the God who breathed life into every withered leaf and every distant star.  </p>
<p>He didn’t want to pray. Not out loud. Not like this.  </p>
<p>But something in him nudged.<br />
Persistent. Gentle. Familiar.  </p>
<p>After a long hesitation, he shifted, trying to bow his head to the dirt. His snout bumped the ground first, ruining the motion.<br />
He huffed, frustrated, and eventually rested his muzzle against the earth instead, eyes closed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“…God,” he whispered, voice small.<br />
  “I know You’re here. I know You are. Just… don’t leave me. Please.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The words came stilted, awkward, pulled straight from a heart too tired to dress them up.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I don’t know what’s happening. Or where I’m going. Or why I don’t feel the way I should.”<br />
  “But I want You. I want You with me. I want You to have Your way—even if I mess everything else up.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>His throat tightened. His body quivered—though not from the cold.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Just stay. Don’t let me disappoint You.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He prayed until the words ran dry—until everything inside him had been poured bare.  </p>
<p>And when the words gave out, he gave way to something else that filled the silence.  </p>
<p>Soft at first, then fuller.  </p>
<p>Not English.<br />
Not any language he knew.  </p>
<p>A trembling flow of syllables shaped entirely by surrender.  </p>
<p>Joseph stayed there, chin against the dirt, blanket wrapped tight around his shaking shoulders, praying in tongues beneath a sky full of stars.  </p>
<h3 id="stirring">Stirring</h3>
<p>Snout padded through the grass, following the faint trail Joseph had left when he wandered off.<br />
His scent clung low to the ground: tired musk, camp-smoke, and that strange edge she still couldn’t name.  </p>
<p>She was coming to fetch him.  </p>
<p>But she slowed.  </p>
<p>Long before she saw him.  </p>
<p>Her ears twitched, then pinned halfway back.<br />
The fur along her spine lifted without permission.<br />
The air felt… wrong. Not dangerous, exactly—just charged, humming, like the moment before lightning strikes.<br />
A faint buzzing crawled across her skin, prickling the tips of her whiskers.<br />
Heat pressed at her chest, coiling tight in her lungs.  </p>
<p>She stopped walking.  </p>
<p>Her throat tightened—not from pain, but from some nameless instinct she’d never felt before.<br />
It wasn’t the cold, or anything she knew.<br />
Just… a pressure in the open air.<br />
Her instincts recoiled, the same way they did before storms or sickness.  </p>
<p>Fear?<br />
No, not quite.<br />
Anger?<br />
Not that either, but it flickered at the edges.<br />
A strange repulsion twisted in her gut, like some part of her recoiled without knowing the reason.  </p>
<p>For a heartbeat she thought she was imagining it.  </p>
<p>Then she took one more step.  </p>
<p>And saw him.  </p>
<p>The fox laid low to the ground, blanket wrapped around him, head on the ground as though asleep.<br />
Small. Unremarkable.<br />
Yet the moment she laid eyes on him, the buzzing sharpened—hotter, louder—like sparks crackling just under her skin.  </p>
<p>It was coming from him.  </p>
<p>Snout blinked, breath stuttering, confusion warring with a sudden instinct to back away.<br />
Nothing about him looked threatening.<br />
Nothing explained the pressure behind her ribs.  </p>
<p>She stepped forward anyway.  </p>
<p>The grass rustled beneath her paw.  </p>
<p>Joseph turned at the sound, his ears perked, eyes soft with the faint glow of someone pulled from deep thought.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh. Hi,” he said simply—<br />
  as if nothing at all had just shaken the air around him.  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="tenseair">Tense Air</h3>
<p>Snout didn’t speak.<br />
Neither did Joseph.  </p>
<p>Snout just stood there, staring at him with a look he couldn’t name—ears half-pinned, pupils tight, as if she were trying to figure out what he was.<br />
Joseph shifted under the weight of it.  </p>
<p><em>Is there something on me?</em><br />
He pulled the blanket tighter, brushing at his fur. Nothing.  </p>
<p>Her gaze didn’t move.  </p>
<p>He glanced behind him. <em>Is something coming?</em><br />
Just grass, dim twilight, and the quiet sigh of the wind.  </p>
<p>His sight returned to her, and still she stared.  </p>
<p>“…Is something wrong?” he finally asked.  </p>
<p>Snout flinched—barely, but he caught it. Her answer came too sharp, snapping out like a twig under strain.  </p>
<p>“You shouldn’t be out here. It’s getting cold.”  </p>
<p>Joseph blinked, unsure why she sounded irritated.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh. Sorry. I just… needed a minute. To think.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Her shoulders eased by a hair. When she spoke again, her tone was steadier, more practiced.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Supper’s ready.”  </p>
  <p>“Alright. Thanks,” Joseph said with a faint smile.<br />
  “I’ll be over in a second.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout didn’t linger.<br />
She turned quickly, paws brushing through the grass as she moved back toward camp—too fast to be casual, as if distance itself was a relief, as if the air around him was something she needed to escape.  </p>
<h3 id="return">Return</h3>
<p>Joseph remained where he was for a moment longer.  </p>
<p>The presence settled over him again—warm, gentle, steady.<br />
Like being wrapped in a blanket that reached deeper than fur or skin.<br />
The earlier tension drained from his shoulders, replaced by a slow, quiet peace.<br />
No buzzing, no heat, no fear. Just stillness.  </p>
<p>Just God… near.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Thank You,” he whispered.<br />
  “For staying with me.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The wind stirred softly through the clearing, as if in answer.  </p>
<p>After another breath, Joseph stood, gathered the blanket, and made his way back toward the glow of the campfire.  </p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Blaze the Star</name>
            <email>startheblaze@gmail.com</email>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revival Ch.3]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/3</id>
        <link href="https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/3"/>
        <updated>2026-01-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="coldcanvas">Cold Canvas</h3>
<p>Joseph woke to cold air threading through the seams of the tent.  </p>
<p>For a moment he didn’t know where he was.  </p>
<p>Canvas above him.<br />
A blanket t...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="coldcanvas">Cold Canvas</h3>
<p>Joseph woke to cold air threading through the seams of the tent.  </p>
<p>For a moment he didn’t know where he was.  </p>
<p>Canvas above him.<br />
A blanket tangled around his legs.<br />
The faint ache in his back from sleeping curled too tightly.<br />
Then the smell of cedar and last night’s fire settled his thoughts, grounding him in the small clearing just outside Flint Water.  </p>
<p>His paws were stiff.<br />
His breath fogged.<br />
And his tail—still something he hadn’t accepted as his—was pinned beneath him again.  </p>
<p>He exhaled, shifting until it freed itself, and pushed upright, rubbing his eyes with the back of one paw.<br />
Outside, voices drifted in and out of the morning air—low, tired, familiar.  </p>
<p>He slipped out through the tent flap.  </p>
<p>Snout, Chatter, and Fight were gathered near the fire, each with a piece of dry bread in paw.<br />
Not toasted.<br />
Not warmed.<br />
Just… dry.<br />
The smell of it was faintly sour and faintly old.  </p>
<p>Chatter didn’t seem to mind.  </p>
<p>The otter was already halfway through his, crumbs clinging to his whiskers.  </p>
<p>Snout glanced up as Joseph approached, her coyote ears flicking in greeting.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“‘Mornin’, fox.”  </p>
  <p>“Morning,” Joseph murmured.    </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He tugged his blanket close, shivering as the cold slipped straight through his fur.<br />
He eased down beside the fire, soaking in what little warmth it offered.  </p>
<p>Fight tossed him a chunk of bread—none too gently.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>The bobcat muttered, “Eat. We’ve got a long day.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph caught it against his chest, trying not to wince at the stale hardness.  </p>
<p>Chatter brightened.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Market day!”<br />
  “Lots of noise.”<br />
  “Lots of smells.”<br />
  “Lots of people.”<br />
  “Lots of—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout thumped her tail lightly against the ground.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Let ’im wake up first.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter blinked.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh. Right. Sorry.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph offered a soft smile.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“It’s okay. Just… slow morning.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight snorted like he didn’t understand what a slow morning was.  </p>
<h3 id="marchingorders">Marching Orders</h3>
<p>They ate quietly for a while, the only sounds the crackle of the low fire and Chatter’s occasional hums as he tried to remember a tune.<br />
Joseph watched the faint sunrise leak through the trees, pale gold and washed in cool autumn blue.  </p>
<p>It was the kind of morning that felt older than it was.  </p>
<p>The kind that said the world was already busy whether you were ready or not.  </p>
<p>Footsteps approached.  </p>
<p>Eli emerged from behind the tents, tying the last knot in his pack straps.<br />
His red wolf posture was already alert, keen, his shoulders squared in a way that said he’d been awake long before the rest of them.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Alright,” he said, voice level.<br />
  “Eat up. We’ve got business today.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout straightened.<br />
Chatter perked.<br />
Fight leaned back, unimpressed but listening.  </p>
<p>Eli nodded toward the road.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Snout, Chatter—you’re taking Joseph into town. Market’s open early on third-day.”<br />
  “Get what we need for the week. Food, bandages, lamp-oil. If the price is decent, pick up another coat.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter’s eyes shot wide.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“For him?” He pointed at Joseph.<br />
  “’Cause he shivers all the—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout elbowed him lightly.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Eli didn’t comment. He only continued, “Fight, you’re staying to watch camp.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight blinked once, slowly.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Babysittin’, then.”  </p>
  <p>“Guard duty,” Eli corrected, tone flat.<br />
  “Don’t leave anything unattended. Don’t let anyone wander through.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight shrugged, noncommittal but accepting.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“And you?” Snout asked, brushing crumbs from her paws.  </p>
  <p>“I’m going into town as well,” Eli said, checking the ties on his belt.<br />
  “To see if there are any contracts posted. We’re overdue for paid work.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Something in his voice shifted—quiet, stern.<br />
A different weight beneath the words.  </p>
<p>He scanned the group once, eyes sharp.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“And one more thing.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>All three of them stilled.<br />
Even Chatter quit breathing for a beat.  </p>
<p>Eli’s expression didn’t change, but his tone dropped—low, certain, unyielding.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“No one in Flint Water hears that Joseph was human.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="wrongpeople">Wrong People</h3>
<p>Snout’s ears pricked.<br />
Chatter looked confused.<br />
Fight raised a brow.  </p>
<p>Joseph felt a cold flicker in his chest.  </p>
<p>Snout asked first.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Why? Folks won’t believe it anyhow.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli hesitated—not long, but long enough to be noticeable.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Because,” he said, choosing each word like he was setting down something fragile,<br />
  “the wrong people would want him. And I’m not interested in handing him over to anyone.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter swallowed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Who’s the ‘wrong people’?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli’s jaw tightened.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Just keep his secret. That’s enough.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Silence followed, heavy and uneasy.  </p>
<p>Then Eli straightened.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Finish eating. We move in ten minutes.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He turned toward the road, the dawn light catching the edges of his fur, and walked off without another word.  </p>
<p>Joseph watched him go, the bread forgotten in his paws.<br />
A tight, nameless knot curled in his stomach.  </p>
<p>He didn’t understand this place.<br />
And right now, he wasn’t sure he wanted to.  </p>
<h3 id="intoflintwater">Into Flint Water</h3>
<p>Flint Water rose out of the fields in a jumble of stone, timber, and smoke.  </p>
<p>The closer they walked, the tighter everything seemed to pinch inward—dirt roads narrowing into pressed, foot-worn paths, buildings crowding shoulder to shoulder as though competing for what little space the town allowed.  </p>
<p>Joseph stayed close behind Snout and Chatter, trying not to drift or draw attention.  </p>
<p>Animals moved around them in steady streams: coyotes, bobcats, foxes, a few raccoons and badgers.<br />
All roughly Snout’s size or Fight’s height, all walking upright with the effortless confidence Joseph wished he had.<br />
Joseph shifted his grip on the walking stick at his side, the wood tapping lightly against the ground as he tried to match their pace.  </p>
<p>The streets were too narrow for carts.<br />
Everything was foot traffic—boots and pawpads scuffing earth, tails brushing coats, merchants calling from doorways stacked with crates and woven baskets.  </p>
<p>Storefronts pressed tight together, each one with hand-painted signs, wooden counters, and open windows spilling out smells of spice, leather, and warm grain.  </p>
<p>A sudden swell of pedestrians pressed in from a side street, jostling them.<br />
Joseph blinked—Snout vanished behind a moving wall of bodies for half a second.  </p>
<p>His heart kicked, but he hurried two steps forward and her ears reappeared—Snout weaving ahead with sure, purposeful strides.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“This way,” she said, weaving through a knot of pedestrians.<br />
  “Main market’s just ahead.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter trailed beside Joseph, nearly vibrating with excitement.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Keep up, yeah? Flint Water’s tiny, but it’s a maze if you’re new.”<br />
  “Got turned ’round once when I was seven—Snout had to find me by scent.”<br />
  He brightened. “Took her three minutes.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout tossed a look over her shoulder.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Only ’cause you hid.”  </p>
  <p>“Strategically,” Chatter insisted.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph managed a small smile but kept his eyes forward.<br />
There was too much to look at.<br />
Too much to learn.<br />
And far too many strangers who seemed to sense he didn’t belong.  </p>
<h3 id="marksmeasures">Marks &amp; Measures</h3>
<p>They reached the main stretch of market stalls, a dense, lively strip where voices overlapped in sharp waves.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Dried roots! Four bundles a mark!”  </p>
  <p>“Fresh cloth! No moth-holes, I swear it!”  </p>
  <p>“Two jars for one if you buy before fourth bell!”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout approached a vendor selling oil flasks.  </p>
<p>She crossed her arms, ears angled back—a stance Joseph recognized by now: <em>about to haggle</em>.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“How much for three?”  </p>
  <p>“Six marks,” the raccoon behind the counter replied.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout scoffed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“They were four last week.”  </p>
  <p>“Then you should’ve bought ’em last week.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter leaned over the counter eagerly.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What if we buy four? Does that—”  </p>
  <p>“Chatter.” Snout’s tone had the weight of an older sibling.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He closed his mouth.  </p>
<p>Five minutes later, she walked away with four flasks for five marks, smugness flicking in her tail-tip.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>Chatter whispered to Joseph, “I helped. By stayin’ quiet.”  </p>
  <p>“You did good,” Snout said dryly.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>They wound farther through the market, gathering bandages, a coat, and a few small food staples.<br />
Joseph carried what he could without slowing them, sticking close enough that his arm brushed Chatter’s once or twice.  </p>
<p>He didn’t want to lose them.  </p>
<p>Not in this crowd.  </p>
<p>Not in a place where every face felt unfamiliar.  </p>
<h3 id="lost">Lost</h3>
<p>They shopped for another hour, weaving through pockets of noise and shifting crowds.<br />
Snout bartered for dried fruit, then for flint, then for a tightly sealed jar of ointment whose smell made Joseph’s eyes water.  </p>
<p>Chatter tried to convince a vendor to include a free wooden spoon “for luck,” and somehow succeeded.<br />
Joseph followed close behind, clutching the items he carried—a coat pressed to his chest, a small parcel of salve, and a handful of wrapped bandages.  </p>
<p>Joseph realized he was drifting half a step behind, the press of bodies nudging him off balance.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Wait—hold on—”<br />
  But his voice was swallowed by the noise.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He shifted the goods in his arms, trying not to drop them.<br />
Snout’s ears flicked ahead—then dipped out of sight behind a tall badger shouldering his way through the lane.  </p>
<p>Joseph quickened his pace.  </p>
<p>He tried to angle around the badger—only for a pair of raccoons to cross in front of him.  </p>
<p>He pivoted left, thinking Snout had gone that way.  </p>
<p>Then right, catching a glimpse of brown fur—only to realize it wasn’t Chatter at all.  </p>
<p>The market twisted around him, every path looking the same, every face unfamiliar.  </p>
<p>He turned again, heart picking up, trying to remember which direction they’d been walking—  </p>
<p>—and the crowd surged.  </p>
<p>Pedestrians pushed between them—bodies brushing, tails flicking, voices overlapping.  </p>
<p>In seconds he couldn’t tell where he’d come from, much less where Snout and Chatter had gone.  </p>
<p>He spun in place.  </p>
<p>Nothing.  </p>
<p>Only strangers.  </p>
<p>All moving in different directions.  </p>
<p>All too tall, too confident, too knowing of this place.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s breath hitched.  </p>
<p>He pivoted again, scanning the sea of bodies, looking for any glint of familiar fur.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Snout?” he called under his breath.<br />
  “Chatter?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>No answer.  </p>
<p>No space to even step out of the flow without getting jostled again.  </p>
<p>He clutched the parcel tighter.  </p>
<p>His heartbeat skittered.  </p>
<p><em>What do I do? Should I stay put? Should I move? They could be anywhere by now, I—</em>  </p>
<p>A ripple moved through the street.  </p>
<h3 id="smokesilence">Smoke &amp; Silence</h3>
<p>A hush—brief, sharp—fell across the stalls.  </p>
<p>Voices stilled.  </p>
<p>Movement slowed.  </p>
<p>Then came the call:  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Make way! Prepare! Clear the path!”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The crowd shifted as one, pressing to the sides of the street.<br />
Joseph was swept along with them, bumping shoulders, nearly dropping his bundle.<br />
He staggered back, finding himself against the front of a closed shop.  </p>
<p>Down the center of the road came a robed wolf, staff held high, clearing space with authoritative sweeps.  </p>
<p>Behind him, two figures walked in perfect unison, swinging bronze censers from short chains.<br />
Smoke trailed from them in curling ribbons, sweet and sharp, perfuming the air.  </p>
<p>Behind them came a platform borne by two strong-backed coyotes.<br />
On it rested a statue—tall and polished, carved from metal or stone; Joseph couldn’t tell.<br />
Its expression was serene, its many-fingered hands outstretched.  </p>
<p>Four more robed figures surrounded it, each holding an ornate staff capped with carved shapes that glinted in the sun.  </p>
<p>The crowd murmured, but reverently.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s skin prickled.  </p>
<p>A tightness coiled under his ribs.  </p>
<p><em>They’ll expect me to… do something.</em><br />
<em>Bow, touch the dirt, pray.</em><br />
<em>I can’t.</em><br />
<em>I can’t do any of that.</em>  </p>
<h3 id="allkneel">All Kneel</h3>
<p>The procession slowed as it neared his part of the street.  </p>
<p>The lead figure lifted his staff high.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“All kneel!”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>A wave of movement swept outward like a falling curtain.  </p>
<p>Every animal around Joseph bent to their knees or lowered their bodies, heads bowed low, eyes shut.  </p>
<p>Joseph froze.  </p>
<p>His breath left him in a hard, shaky puff.  </p>
<p>He let the items slip from his arms; they hit the dirt with a soft thud.  </p>
<p>But he did not bow.  </p>
<p>A lynx beside him hissed under her breath.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You have to,” she whispered urgently.<br />
  “They’ll see.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph swallowed, but he couldn’t make his body move.  </p>
<p>Even if he wanted to bow—<em>even if he tried</em>—something in him held him upright.<br />
Like an invisible hand bracing his spine.  </p>
<p>Footsteps approached.  </p>
<p>One of the robed guards peeled away from the procession, staff angled forward like a threat.<br />
His hood hid his eyes, but Joseph could feel the glare all the same.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You,” the figure snapped.<br />
  “Why don’t you bow?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s mouth dried.  </p>
<p>His heart pounded disordered beats.  </p>
<p>He searched frantically for an excuse—<br />
<em>I didn’t hear,</em><br />
<em>I didn’t know,</em><br />
<em>My knees—</em>  </p>
<p>Anything but the truth.  </p>
<p>But then, somewhere in the panic, a quiet thought settled over him:  </p>
<p><em>Tell the truth.</em>  </p>
<p>Joseph trembled.  </p>
<p>He didn’t think it would help.<br />
He didn’t think anything would.  </p>
<p>But he whispered anyway, voice barely steady:  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“M-My God doesn’t allow me to bow.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="wind">Wind</h3>
<p>For a heartbeat, the street went dead silent.  </p>
<p>The robed figure froze.  </p>
<p>His grip tightened on the staff—holding it close to his chest.<br />
His hooded face angled toward Joseph, studying him.  </p>
<p>Not surprised.<br />
Not confused.  </p>
<p>Weighing.  </p>
<p>The air thinned.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s pulse hammered in his ears.<br />
He couldn’t read the expression beneath the hood, but something shifted—like the wolf was deciding whether Joseph was ignorant… or defiant.  </p>
<p>A slow inhale drew through the figure’s teeth.  </p>
<p>Then his shoulders squared.  </p>
<p>Decision made.  </p>
<p>His lips peeled back in a quiet, controlled snarl.  </p>
<p>With sudden violence, he raised his staff high, ready to bring it down toward Joseph’s skull.  </p>
<p>Joseph flinched—his cover slipping to the dirt as his paws shot up by instinct.  </p>
<p>Then—<strong>wind</strong>.  </p>
<p>Short.  </p>
<p>Sudden.  </p>
<p>Not harsh—just enough to rattle signs, lift dust, and send cloaks fluttering.  </p>
<p>Everyone felt it.  </p>
<p>The robed figure froze mid-strike.  </p>
<p>Joseph slowly lowered his paws.  </p>
<p>He couldn’t see the wolf’s eyes, but he could see the muzzle beneath the hood—hanging agape in shock.  </p>
<p>Then, without a word, the figure backed away.  </p>
<p>Turned sharply.  </p>
<p>And rejoined the procession as though nothing had happened.  </p>
<p>Joseph stood trembling, surrounded by a kneeling crowd and scattered belongings in the dirt, wondering what—exactly—had happened.  </p>
<h3 id="marked">Marked</h3>
<p>One by one, the creatures around him began to rise.  </p>
<p>First a fox, then a lynx, then a broad-shouldered badger—each lifting their head, dusting off their knees, casting uneasy glances in Joseph’s direction.<br />
Whispers rippled through the street like wind through dry grass.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Is he cursed?”<br />
  “No… look at him. That was protection.”<br />
  “By what?”<br />
  “By <em>whom</em>?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Dozens of eyes fixed on him—wide, darting, curious, wary.<br />
Joseph swallowed hard.<br />
Standing among them, he suddenly felt just how small he was.<br />
The tallest of them towered over him; even the shortest came up nearly to his ears.<br />
He felt like a child who had wandered into a crowd of adults.  </p>
<p>His heart hammered against his ribs.  </p>
<p>His legs trembled so badly he wasn’t sure they’d hold.  </p>
<p>He spun, scanning the crowd for Snout’s spotted coat or Chatter’s tail.<br />
Still, nothing.<br />
No familiar shapes.<br />
No anchors.  </p>
<p><em>I need to get out.  
I need to get away—now.</em>  </p>
<p>Before he could lose his nerve, he lunged forward, snatching up the fallen parcel with clumsy paws.<br />
A gap opened beside a fruit stall—a narrow, shadowed alley between buildings.  </p>
<p>He took it.  </p>
<p>He squeezed through, leaving the murmurs and stares behind, half-running, half-stumbling until the street noise faded to a distant hum.<br />
Only when he was deep enough that no one could see him did he stop.  </p>
<p>The goods slipped from his arms and thudded to the ground.<br />
Joseph pressed himself against the wall and curled in on himself, head between his paws.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh God… oh God…”    </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He had no other words—only the shaking that wouldn’t stop, only the fear still ricocheting inside his chest.  </p>
<p>He stayed like that for a long moment, breaths coming shallow.  </p>
<p>Then a shift of shadow caught his eye.  </p>
<h3 id="onewhowatched">One Who Watched</h3>
<p>A figure stood at the mouth of the alley he’d come from—motionless, watching.  </p>
<p>The figure stepped closer, something draped over one arm.  </p>
<p>A blanket.<br />
<strong>His</strong> blanket.  </p>
<p>Joseph blinked—then jolted.  </p>
<p>He didn't realize he lost it.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Snout…?” he whispered, desperate.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>His nose twitched as he sat up.  </p>
<p>But the scent hit him: warm earth, sharp frost, and a faint fruity sweetness he didn’t recognize.<br />
Nothing like Snout.<br />
Nothing like Fight or Chatter.<br />
No one familiar.  </p>
<p>The figure slipped into the thin light, revealing the tall, slender shape of a red fox, fur brushed smooth and gleaming copper in the dim.  </p>
<p>Her gaze was direct, unblinking.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You forgot this,” she said gently, holding the blanket out.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph hesitated, then reached for it with trembling paws.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“…Thanks.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Just as he pulled it toward himself, another head popped into the alley—  </p>
<p>Chatter, panting, whiskers frazzled.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“There you are!”<br />
  “I’ve been lookin’ everywhere!”<br />
  “I thought something awful happened—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He halted, breath catching as he finally saw Joseph was safe.    </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Next time warn me if you’re gonna do the whole ‘strategic hidin’’ routine, yeah?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then he noticed the stranger, and his posture hiccuped.    </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Uh… who’re you?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The red fox didn’t look at Chatter.<br />
Her gaze stayed locked on Joseph’s.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re the one from the square,” she said softly.<br />
  “The one who didn’t bow.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He rose to his feet abruptly, gripping the blanket tight against his chest like it might shield him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I—I don’t want any more trouble,” he managed.  </p>
  <p>“Trouble?” She laughed. Musical. Effortless.<br />
  “No, little one. Quite the opposite.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter blinked rapidly.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Little one? He’s—well, okay, he is kinda small, but still—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The fox stepped closer, her tail curling briefly at Joseph’s feet like a test.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“That took courage,” she said.<br />
  “Foolish courage, maybe. But courage all the same.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s ears flattened.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I didn’t… I didn’t do it to be brave.”  </p>
  <p>“I know.”<br />
  She tilted her head, studying him with unsettling precision.<br />
  “You did it because you couldn’t do anything else.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="cute">Cute</h3>
<p>Chatter leaned sideways toward Joseph and whispered—loudly—  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Is she… is she flirtin’ with you?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nearly choked on his own breath.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I don’t— I don’t think— stop talking.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>She smiled, slow and knowing.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re cute when you panic.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s whole body bristled.<br />
Chatter made a strangled little squeak.  </p>
<p>She stepped back just enough to give Joseph room, but her eyes never left him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“My name’s Crystal,” she murmured.<br />
  “And you…?”  </p>
  <p>“J–Joseph,” he stuttered.  </p>
  <p>“Joseph.”<br />
  She tasted the name like it was something sweet.<br />
  “It suits you.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph shifted, suddenly desperate to escape before he collapsed into the bricks behind him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I— Thank you for the blanket,” he said quickly.<br />
  “I should go.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Crystal’s smile softened—not mocking now, but curious, almost thoughtful.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I hope I see you again,” she said.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph didn’t answer.<br />
He pulled the blanket around his shoulders, gathered his parcel, and slipped past Chatter, heart hammering.  </p>
<p>Chatter scrambled after him, whispering frantically,  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Joseph, what just happened? Who was she? Did she really call you cute? Did you hear her—”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph just kept walking, ears burning, refusing to look back.  </p>
<p>Behind them, in the dim alley, Crystal watched him leave—quiet, unreadable—eyes flickering with interest that hadn’t dimmed in the slightest.  </p>
<p>Chatter and Joseph stepped out of the narrow alley and into the open street.<br />
Cool air brushed Joseph's fur, and the distant hum of voices reminded him how loud the world was outside Crystal’s shadow.  </p>
<p>That was when he realized.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh no…”  </p>
  <p>“Huh?” Chatter chirped.<br />
  "What is it? Are you hurt?"  </p>
  <p>"I lost my stick."</p>
</blockquote>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Blaze the Star</name>
            <email>startheblaze@gmail.com</email>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revival Ch.4]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/4</id>
        <link href="https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/4"/>
        <updated>2026-01-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="homecoming">Homecoming</h3>
<p>The camp came back into view just as the sun tipped past its highest point, light slanting through the trees in long, pale bars.<br />
Smoke still curled faintly...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="homecoming">Homecoming</h3>
<p>The camp came back into view just as the sun tipped past its highest point, light slanting through the trees in long, pale bars.<br />
Smoke still curled faintly from the fire pit—Fight hadn’t let it die while they were gone.</p>
<p>The bobcat looked up as they approached, arms crossed, tail flicking once.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re back,” he said.<br />
  “Camp’s still here. No raids. No fires. No excitement.” 
  A beat.<br />
  “You’re welcome.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout dipped her head in thanks and set the bundles down near the fire.<br />
Chatter dropped his load with a grunt, already reaching for the dry bread left behind.</p>
<p>Joseph lingered, suddenly unsure where to put himself.</p>
<p>Snout noticed.</p>
<p>Joseph lingered, suddenly unsure where to put himself.</p>
<p>Snout noticed.</p>
<p>She stepped in without comment, gently easing the bundle from his arms—bandages, salve, and the folded coat shifting as she sorted them with practiced efficiency.<br />
She set the supplies down by the fire, then lifted the coat free and turned back to him.</p>
<p>She held it out.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Here,” she said. “Try it.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph hesitated, then slipped his arms into it.<br />
The fabric was worn but sturdy, lined enough that warmth settled around him almost immediately—no drafts, no biting chill.<br />
For the first time since waking in this body, he didn’t need to clutch his blanket or hunch in on himself.</p>
<p>His shoulders loosened without him meaning to.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oh,” he breathed.<br />
  “It’s… warm.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Chatter beamed like he stitched it himself.</p>
<p>Fight watched him for a long moment, then grunted.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Huh. Looks like you belong now.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Before Joseph could respond, footsteps sounded on the path.</p>
<p>Eli emerged from the trees, pack slung low, eyes already scanning the camp.<br />
When they landed on Joseph—upright, coated, alive—something tight in his posture eased.</p>
<p>But not all the way.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Snout,” Eli said, quiet. “A word.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>She stiffened, then followed him a few steps away.</p>
<p>Fight leaned closer to Joseph, voice dropping.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Alright,” he said.<br />
  “What’d you do?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph blinked.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I—what?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight jerked his chin toward Eli and Snout.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“He only pulls someone aside like that when something’s wrong. So.”<br />
  “What went wrong?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph opened his mouth, then closed it, heat creeping up his ears.</p>
<p>Chatter tilted his head.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Well, he did disappear for like… ten minutes,” he offered.
  “I mean—I hid on purpose once, and Snout found me in three.”
  “But this doesn’t feel like an Eli-level worry.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout returned a moment later, expression unreadable.</p>
<p>She stopped in front of Joseph.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Eli wants to talk to you,” she said gently.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight winced.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oof,” he muttered.<br />
  “You’re in trouble.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph swallowed.</p>
<p>Then, clutching the edge of his new coat like a lifeline, he turned and walked toward Eli.</p>
<h3 id="whatwasheard">What Was Heard</h3>
<p>Eli stood just beyond the edge of camp, where the ground dipped slightly and the trees thickened.<br />
He had removed his pack and set it aside, posture looser than before—but his eyes were sharp when Joseph approached.</p>
<p>He waited until Joseph stopped in front of him.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You alright?” Eli asked.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded quickly.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Yes. I’m fine.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli didn’t respond right away. He watched Joseph’s ears, the way his paws worried at the edge of his coat.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Did anything happen in town?” he asked.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s chest tightened.</p>
<p>He knew he should answer.<br />
Knew this was the moment.</p>
<p>Instead, he stalled.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“W-what do you mean?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli’s jaw set—not angry. Just firm.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I heard there was a swift fox in the market,” he said.<br />
  “Didn’t bow during a shrine walk.”<br />
  “Almost got struck for it.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph closed his eyes--head dipped.</p>
<p>For a long second, he said nothing.<br />
Then his shoulders slumped.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“…Yes,” he admitted quietly.<br />
  “That was me.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli inhaled slowly.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Are you hurt?”</p>
  <p>“No.”<br />
  The answer came too fast—reflexive.<br />
  “I’m not hurt.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Another pause.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“That was a shrine walk,” Eli said.<br />
  “They don’t tolerate defiance. Not public. Not there.”<br />
  “What you did was dangerous.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded, staring at the dirt.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I know.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>His voice wavered, but he kept going.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I know it put everyone at risk.”<br />
  “I know it makes things harder.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>His claws curled into the fabric of his coat.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“But I couldn’t do it,” he whispered.<br />
  “I can’t go against God.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The words came out small.<br />
Fragile.<br />
And beneath them—fear.</p>
<p><em>Not of punishment.</em><br />
Of being a burden.</p>
<p>Eli studied him for a long moment.</p>
<p>Then, deliberately, he lowered himself to his haunches—bringing his gaze closer to Joseph’s level.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What you did wasn’t wrong,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph looked up, startled.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“But it was dangerous,” Eli continued.<br />
  “So next time—if there is a next time—you hide.”<br />
  “Run, if you need to.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded, clutching his coat tighter.</p>
<p>Eli let the silence sit, giving him space to breathe.</p>
<p>Then he stood.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“We’ll set some rules,” he said.<br />
  “Make sure this doesn’t happen again.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He turned back toward camp.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Come on,” he added gently.<br />
  “Let’s not keep the others waiting.”</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="section3">Section 3</h3>
<p>Eli and Joseph returned to the heart of camp together.</p>
<p>The others looked up as they approached—Fight first, then Snout, then Chatter—reading the set of Eli’s shoulders before he said anything at all.<br />
He didn’t raise his voice. He didn’t soften it either.<br />
He laid out the rules plainly, without flourish or justification, as though they had always existed and were only now being spoken aloud.</p>
<p>Joseph would not go into Flint Water again.<br />
Not for now.<br />
Not until Eli said otherwise.</p>
<p>No one argued.<br />
Fight gave a single grunt of acknowledgment.<br />
Snout’s ears dipped in understanding.<br />
Chatter opened his mouth, then thought better of it and closed it again.</p>
<p>Joseph nodded along with them, the motion small and tight.<br />
The boundary settled over him with the weight of something both restrictive and necessary.<br />
It felt, distantly, like being grounded—but he understood.<br />
The town was not a place that would give him second chances.<br />
Whatever had stayed the priest’s hand once might not do so again.</p>
<p>The day moved forward regardless.</p>
<p>%% Find somewhere in the next montage to include the nearby lake. Maybe they wash clothes in it or something. %%</p>
<p>Joseph was given small, harmless tasks—things that kept his paws busy and his presence useful without putting him in the way.<br />
He sorted supplies, stacked bundles by size, swept old ash from the fire pit.<br />
When the pile of kindling ran low, he broke twigs down by hand, the steady crack and snap grounding in its repetition.</p>
<p>He listened more than he spoke.</p>
<p>From where he worked, he could hear Eli and Fight talking in low voices about contracts posted in town—guard work, escort jobs, the kind of labor that paid in coin but carried its own risks.<br />
Names and places drifted past Joseph without sticking.<br />
He wasn’t part of those conversations.<br />
Not yet.<br />
Maybe not ever.</p>
<p>Later, there was nothing left for him to do.</p>
<p>He sat near the fire, blanket folded at his side, Eli never far from view.<br />
The presence was quiet, watchful—not smothering, but constant.</p>
<p>By the time the sun dipped low and the camp shifted into its familiar evening rhythms, the day felt impossibly long.<br />
Like it had stretched itself thin just to wear him down.</p>
<p>Joseph was grateful when night finally came.</p>
<p>As he lay curled beneath the canvas, the quiet crept back in. The stillness should have been comforting.</p>
<p>Instead, the thought settled heavy in his chest:</p>
<p>Tomorrow would be the same.</p>
<p>And that knowledge followed him into sleep, dulling the peace he wanted to feel, lingering like a shadow that refused to fade.</p>
<hr />
<h3 id="section4">Section 4</h3>
<p>Joseph was already awake when he realized Snout was gone.</p>
<p>Her bedroll was packed.<br />
Her space by the fire was cold.<br />
Only the faint scuff of bootprints in the dirt marked that she’d ever been there at all.</p>
<p>Fight was tightening the straps on his pack when he noticed Joseph looking.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Patrol contract,” he said.<br />
  “Town edge. Shrine routes.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The word <em>shrine</em> settled uncomfortably in Joseph’s chest, but nothing more was said. It didn’t need to be.</p>
<p>Chatter, however, did.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Patrolling’s boring,” he announced, pacing wide circles around the fire.<br />
  “You just walk and walk and pretend nothing’s wrong.”<br />
  “Snout’s good at it though. She’s got the serious face.”<br />
  “I’ve got the talking face.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He dropped onto a log beside Joseph with a soft thump.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I grew up on river barges, you know.”<br />
  “Cargo runs mostly. Smelled like fish and wet wood.”<br />
  “Learned knots before letters. Swimming before math.”<br />
  “Fight says that counts as experience.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph huffed a quiet laugh.</p>
<p>Chatter leaned back, staring up through the trees.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Hey, question.”<br />
  “How long does it take a river to carve a canyon?”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph’s mind jumped automatically—<em>erosion rates, geology, years, thousands of—</em><br />
His fingers twitched, already reaching for an answer that should’ve been easy to find.</p>
<p>They closed around nothing.</p>
<p>The thought passed quickly, but it left a hollow behind it. No quick searches. No background knowledge at his fingertips. Just what he remembered—and what he didn’t.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I… don’t know,” he admitted.</p>
  <p>“Huh,” Chatter said, unbothered.<br />
  “Guess I’ll ask someone smarter later.”</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="section5">Section 5</h3>
<p>Fight hoisted his pack.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You comin’ or talkin’ all day?”</p>
  <p>“Both!” Chatter chirped, already scrambling after him.<br />
  “Learning <em>and</em> talking.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They disappeared down the path, voices fading.</p>
<p>The camp settled into stillness.</p>
<p>Joseph stayed where he was.</p>
<p>He tried helping—sorted gear that didn’t need sorting, swept dirt that would only return, snapped kindling down to nothing just to hear it break. When there was truly nothing left, he sat.</p>
<p>And sat.</p>
<p>Eli remained nearby, sharpening a blade, methodical and silent. The scrape of metal on stone marked time more clearly than the sun.</p>
<p>Joseph shifted. Folded his hands. Unfolded them. Stared at the fire pit. At the trees. At nothing in particular.</p>
<p>Boredom crept in slow and heavy, pressing at him from all sides—not the restless kind he knew, but something deeper. There was nowhere to scroll, nothing to check, no noise to fill the gaps between thoughts.</p>
<p>Eventually, he stood.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Would it be alright if I went to the lake for a bit?” he asked.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli looked up, studied him, then nodded once.</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Don’t wander far.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph pulled his coat close and headed toward the water, grateful for the excuse to move—hoping the quiet there would be easier than the stillness he was leaving behind.</p>
<hr />
<h3 id="section6">Section 6</h3>
<p>The trees thinned as Joseph reached the water’s edge.</p>
<p>The lake spread out before him, wide and quiet, its surface broken only by slow ripples and the pale reflection of the sky. Reeds clustered along the shore, their tips whispering softly in the breeze. Somewhere behind him, Flint Water sat tucked beyond the treeline—out of sight, but not out of mind. He could almost feel it there, like pressure at his back.</p>
<p>A flock of birds cut across the sky overhead, wings flashing silver as they turned in unison. Their calls echoed once, then faded, leaving the lake to its hush again.</p>
<p>Joseph exhaled.</p>
<p>He crouched near the shore and picked up a flat stone, weighing it in his paw. The motion felt wrong—his grip clumsy, his balance unfamiliar. Still, he flicked his arm and sent the stone skipping toward the water.</p>
<p>It didn’t skip.</p>
<p>It plunked straight down and vanished.</p>
<p>He frowned and tossed another, but it too sank immediately. A third barely made it past the shoreline.</p>
<p>Joseph’s ears flattened.</p>
<p>He adjusted his stance, mimicking what he remembered—angle, speed, wrist snap—but his fox body didn’t listen the way his old one would have. Each throw felt off by a fraction he couldn’t correct.</p>
<p>Frustration built sharp and fast.</p>
<p>On the next throw, he put too much force behind it. The stone flew—but his footing didn’t hold. His paw slipped on loose gravel, and he stumbled, scraping his arm against a jagged rock.</p>
<p>He hissed and swiped at it furiously.<br />
It tumbled end over end before disappearing into the lake with a dull splash.</p>
<p>He examined the scratch.</p>
<p>Red dots formed a line under the fur.
It stung, but it was nothing serious.</p>
<p>A long heavy sigh escaped between his teeth.</p>
<p>He propped himself onto his haunches, bracing his weight with his front legs, shoulders slumping as the tension drained out of him. The water lapped quietly at the shore, indifferent.</p>
<p>He stared out across the lake, breathing slowing, anger ebbing into something duller.</p>
<p>Just for a moment, he let himself sit there—small against the water, the sky, the distance—watching the ripples smooth themselves out again.</p>
<h3 id="section7">Section 7</h3>
<p>Joseph stared out across the lake.</p>
<p>The water lay smooth and pale beneath the open sky, broken only by slow ripples where the wind brushed its surface. That same wind slid through his fur, cool and steady, lifting it along his arms and down his spine. His ears flicked as it passed, and then—without warning—his coat prickled, every hair standing on end.</p>
<p>Not from cold.</p>
<p>From remembrance.</p>
<p>The sensation caught in his chest, familiar in a way that had nothing to do with this body. The same quiet weight. The same unseen nearness. The Holy Spirit—here, with him, as surely as ever.</p>
<p>Joseph lowered himself to the ground. It was awkward, clumsy—his best attempt at bowing in a form not made for it—but he pressed his head low all the same, forelegs folded beneath him, posture offered rather than perfected.</p>
<p>He closed his eyes.</p>
<p><em>Blessed are You, my Lord.</em></p>
<p>The words formed without strain, rising gently from somewhere deeper than thought.</p>
<p><em>I love You.</em><br />
<em>I worship You.</em></p>
<p>The wind moved again. Time loosened its grip.</p>
<p>Minutes slipped past unnoticed, marked only by the slow rhythm of his breath and the faint sounds of water and distant birds. His prayer did not hurry. It rested.</p>
<p>Eventually, words gave way to something softer.</p>
<p>A whisper—almost a hum.</p>
<p>“I am Yours,” he breathed.<br />
“I am Yours.”<br />
“I am Yours.”</p>
<p>The phrase circled back on itself, over and over, until it felt less like speech and more like truth being remembered.</p>
<p>“You are good,” he whispered.<br />
“You are good.”<br />
“You are good.”</p>
<p>The wind stirred his fur again.</p>
<p>“You are so, so good.”</p>
<p>More time passed. The world did not interrupt him.</p>
<p>A quiet ache rose then—gentle, but real.</p>
<p>“Please,” he murmured, voice small. “Don’t leave me here.”</p>
<p>And in the stillness that followed, his mind filled with light.</p>
<p>He imagined Christ—not dim or distant, but radiant, standing in a place washed through with glory. Joseph could not describe the space around Him; it hardly mattered. All he noticed was the smile—warm, knowing, full of a love that reached him completely.</p>
<p>He imagined holding His hands.</p>
<p>In that moment, there was no awareness of fur or stone or aching limbs. No thought of form at all.</p>
<p>Only this:</p>
<p>He was present with the Lord.</p>
<p>And it was enough.</p>
<h3 id="section8">Section 8</h3>
<p>The world came back all at once.</p>
<p>Not gently—<em>yanked</em>.</p>
<p>Joseph’s awareness slammed into his body like he’d been pulled backward by the shoulders. His breath caught sharp in his chest, heart stuttering as if he’d been shaken awake mid-step. For a dizzy instant, it felt like motion—like falling forward—despite the fact that he hadn’t moved at all.</p>
<p>A loud sound echoed across the lake.</p>
<p>His eyes flew open.</p>
<p>Joseph jerked upright from his bowed position, fur bristling, head snapping toward the noise before his thoughts could catch up. His pulse hammered, the lingering warmth of prayer torn away too quickly, leaving his limbs heavy and disoriented.</p>
<p>Water splashed again.</p>
<p>There—down the shore.</p>
<p>A black fox stood knee-deep at the lake’s edge, sleeves rolled, a wicker basket set on a flat stone nearby. She lifted a soaked garment and wrung it out with practiced force before dipping it back beneath the surface. Wet fabric slapped water. Ripples spread outward.</p>
<p>She was washing clothes.</p>
<p>Joseph exhaled slowly. Once. Twice. He forced his breathing to even out, willing his heart to settle back into his chest where it belonged.</p>
<p><em>It’s fine,</em> he told himself. <em>Just… someone working.</em></p>
<p>He turned his gaze back to the lake, fixing on the far water as if it demanded his full attention. He made a point of looking occupied—studying the surface, the light, anything but her.</p>
<p><em>She’ll leave eventually.</em></p>
<p>Time passed. A few minutes, maybe more. The splashing stopped.</p>
<p>From the corner of his eye, he saw her rise, gathering the damp clothes into her basket. For a hopeful second, it looked like she might turn away and go.</p>
<p>Instead, she paused.</p>
<p>Joseph felt it—the shift of attention, the weight of being noticed. He did not look. He kept his eyes forward, expression carefully neutral.</p>
<p>Footsteps crunched softly against gravel.</p>
<p>She stopped a short distance away.</p>
<p>“You’re that fox from yestereve, ain’t ya?” she said.<br />
The words were edged rough, curious rather than kind.<br />
“The one what stood stiff when the shrine folk passed.”</p>
<h3 id="section9">Section 9</h3>
<p>%% Somewhere in this section,  %%</p>
<p>Joseph turned his head, ears flicking back.</p>
<p>“I–I–”</p>
<p>The dark fox didn’t wait for him to finish.</p>
<p>“That was a stupid thing you did,” she said flatly.<br />
“Near got yourself killed.”</p>
<p>The words landed harder than he expected. Eli’s voice rose unbidden in his memory—<em>dangerous… hide… run if you need to.</em> His chest tightened.</p>
<p>Joseph pushed himself to his feet too quickly, paws scrambling for balance.</p>
<p>“I–I’m sorry,” he blurted. “I should go.”</p>
<p>He had barely turned when her voice caught him again.</p>
<p>“Why’d you do it?”</p>
<p>Joseph stopped.</p>
<p>The lake lapped softly at the shore. Birds cried somewhere far off. He stood there with his back half-turned, coat tugged tight around himself, every instinct telling him to leave—and yet he didn’t.</p>
<p>“I thought you’d be someone lookin’ to make a point,” she went on, puzzled now.<br />
“Rebellious. Loud. Carryin’ an angle.”<br />
Her eyes narrowed slightly.<br />
“But you look like you’re scared of your own fur.”<br />
A pause.<br />
“So why stand like that?”</p>
<p>Joseph swallowed.</p>
<p>Slowly, he turned his head—not fully, not enough to meet her gaze. His eyes stayed low, fixed somewhere near her shoulder.</p>
<p>“I couldn’t,” he said quietly.<br />
A breath.<br />
“I couldn’t betray my God.”</p>
<p>Silence stretched.</p>
<p>When he dared glance up, she was staring at him like he’d stepped out of a story that didn’t belong to this world at all—ears tilted, brow creased, her face crowded with questions she didn’t yet have words for.</p>
<h3 id="section10dangerous">Section 10 — Dangerous</h3>
<p>Pearl didn’t answer him right away.</p>
<p>She stood there with the lake at her back, dark fur stirred by the breeze, eyes fixed on Joseph like she was trying to decide what <em>kind</em> of thing he was.<br />
Not just who—but <em>what</em>.</p>
<p>Her gaze wasn’t cruel.<br />
It wasn’t kind either.</p>
<p>It was the look one gives a blade left out in the open.<br />
Or a flame that hasn’t burned anyone—yet.</p>
<p>Joseph shifted under it, ears twitching, paws digging faint lines into the dirt. He felt suddenly exposed, as though the prayer still clung to him, visible in ways he couldn’t hide.</p>
<p>Pearl’s nose wrinkled, just barely.</p>
<p>“Ya ain’t loud,” she said at last.<br />
“Ya ain’t preachin’.”<br />
“And ya don’t look like someone lookin’ fer trouble.”</p>
<p>She took a step closer—just one.</p>
<p>Her voice dropped.</p>
<p>“That’s what makes ya dangerous.”</p>
<p>The word landed heavier than an insult.<br />
He blinked.</p>
<p>“I—I don’t—” Joseph started, not even sure what he meant to deny.</p>
<p>Pearl shook her head, sharp and final, cutting him off without raising her voice.</p>
<p>“Folks who shout about gods are easy,” she said.<br />
“Folks who bow are easy.”<br />
“Folks who rage, or rebel, or want somethin’—easy.”</p>
<p>Her eyes flicked to his chest. To the place where his heart beat too fast.</p>
<p>“But you stood there shakin’,” she went on.<br />
“And still wouldn’t move.”</p>
<p>The wind slid across the lake, rippling the surface. For a moment, the world felt very still—like it was holding its breath.</p>
<p>Pearl exhaled.</p>
<p>Then she turned.</p>
<p>She picked up her basket, damp cloth shifting inside, and walked past him without another glance. Her steps were quick, purposeful, as if staying any longer risked something she wasn’t ready to face.</p>
<p>Joseph twisted after her.</p>
<p>“Wait—” he said.<br />
“Why?”</p>
<p>She didn’t slow.</p>
<p>Didn’t turn.</p>
<p>Her voice carried back once, low and unsettled.</p>
<p>“Figure it out, fox.”</p>
<p>And then she was gone—<br />
leaving Joseph by the water’s edge, heart pounding, the word <em>dangerous</em> echoing in his chest like a warning he didn’t yet understand.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Blaze the Star</name>
            <email>startheblaze@gmail.com</email>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revival Ch.6 (Draft)]]></title>
        <id>https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/6</id>
        <link href="https://blog.revival.us.kg/1/6"/>
        <updated>2026-01-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snout woke to the sound of leaves shifting overhead—soft, dry, the whisper of fall settled into the trees.  </p>
<p>The air was warmer than yesterday’s bite had promised. Sunlight filtered through ...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Snout woke to the sound of leaves shifting overhead—soft, dry, the whisper of fall settled into the trees.  </p>
<p>The air was warmer than yesterday’s bite had promised. Sunlight filtered through the branches in pale bands, already carrying a hint of heat.  </p>
<p>Eli was gone.  </p>
<p>She knew without checking the far side of camp. The red wolf had a habit of waking before the light properly arrived, slipping out while the world still felt half-finished.  </p>
<p>Snout rose quietly, the packed earth cool beneath her pads, and padded a short distance from the tents.<br />
Her body loosened as she moved—shoulders rolling, spine stretching long and low.<br />
She paced the perimeter once, then again, letting her muscles wake with the ground beneath her.<br />
A short burst of speed followed, then a sudden stop, weight shifting back onto her haunches.<br />
Balance. Readiness.  </p>
<p>She practiced controlled turns, pivots that kept her center low, claws biting into dirt.<br />
A few careful leaps over a fallen branch.<br />
Not flashy. Not for show.<br />
Just keeping her body honest.  </p>
<p>When her breath evened out, she returned to the fire pit.  </p>
<p>The embers from the night before were still there, tucked beneath ash.<br />
She nudged them together with a stick, fed them dry kindling, and breathed gently until the first flame caught.<br />
It grew slow and steady, warmth spreading outward.  </p>
<p>Behind her, fabric rustled.  </p>
<p>Snout glanced over her shoulder.  </p>
<p>Joseph was awake.  </p>
<p>The swift fox barely lifted his head from the ground, ears twitching before settling again.<br />
His eyes looked duller than usual—like he’d already spent his energy somewhere else.  </p>
<p>She lowered her voice.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re up early.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph swallowed and shifted just enough to free one paw.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Yeah,” he murmured.<br />
  “I guess.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout studied him a moment, then turned back to the fire, adjusting a log so it wouldn’t smoke.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You alright?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>There was a pause.<br />
Joseph didn’t look at her.<br />
He took a deep breath instead—slow, careful, like the air weighed something.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I don’t know how to go home.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The words sat there between them, heavier than the quiet.  </p>
<p>Snout felt them land.<br />
Not like panic. Not like grief.<br />
Like something settled too deep to move easily.  </p>
<p>She didn’t answer right away.<br />
Instead, she fed the fire another stick and watched it take, sparks lifting and fading.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“That’s a heavy thing to carry,” she said at last,<br />
  “for something so early in the morning.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph let out a long sigh, shoulders sagging.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“It tends to fade quickly,” he said.<br />
  “Usually around breakfast.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout nodded once.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Then we’ll make sure you eat.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>A short sound escaped Joseph—half laugh, half scoff.<br />
It was quick, surprised, but his mouth softened afterward, the tension easing just a little.  </p>
<p>Footsteps followed.  </p>
<p>Fight pushed out of his tent, fur rumpled, eyes half-lidded.<br />
The bobcat stretched once, claws flexing, then looked between them.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re up early” he said, voice still rough.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded, gaze dropping to the dirt.  </p>
<p>Fight grunted and turned to Snout.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“We got a day patrol job today. Can you take it?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout straightened.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Where?”  </p>
  <p>“Street between Faint Line and Main.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>She groaned, ears flattening.  </p>
<p>Joseph glanced up.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What’s wrong?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout exhaled through her nose.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“That’s where Pearl works,” she said.<br />
  “She’s a troublemaker. And a thief.”<br />
  “Tried to steal from Eli once.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph frowned.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Why don’t you arrest her?”  </p>
  <p>“We did,” Snout replied.<br />
  “She was released. Lack of evidence.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Fight shifted his weight.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You takin’ the job or not?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout hesitated only a moment.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Yeah,” she said.<br />
  “I’ll take it. Just need a minute.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>She turned back to Joseph, her tone softer.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Stay safe.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Joseph nodded, hands curling briefly into his coat as Snout moved off to ready herself for the day, the fire crackling steady behind him as camp slowly began to wake.  </p>
<hr />
<p>The street was more path than road—packed dirt worn into a shallow groove between stone-and-timber storefronts.<br />
The morning traffic moved in a steady, practical stream: merchants dragging crates, laborers crossing with bundles, children darting between legs until a mother’s bark snapped them back.  </p>
<p>A black fox stood in the mouth of her stall like she owned the whole strip.  </p>
<p>Her sign was hand-painted and slightly crooked—<strong>HERBS / SALVES / REMEDIES</strong>—and the shelves behind her were crowded with jars that looked more trustworthy than they deserved to.  </p>
<p>Some were honest: ground willow bark for pain, dried yarrow for bleeding, clean linen wraps.<br />
Others were prettier than useful—sweet syrups that promised strong lungs, charms that claimed to “ward ill wind,” a thin oil that smelled like pine and hope.  </p>
<p>A red fox couple paused at her counter.<br />
The vixen’s eyes were tired; the buck’s limp was subtle but real.  </p>
<p>The dark fox lifted a tin of salve.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“This one’s real,” she said, tapping the lid.<br />
  “Rub it in twice a day.<br />
  It’ll ease the ache. Don’t expect miracles.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The buck nodded.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“And—uh—what about that bottle there?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The dark fox glanced at the amber vial and shrugged.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“That one’s for your spirit.<br />
  If you got coin to spend on feelin’ better, it’ll do the job.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>They laughed and bought both.  </p>
<p>As she wrapped the tin, she kept her tone casual, conversational—like the question mattered no more than the weather.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You two been seein’ a young swift fox around?” she asked.<br />
  “Light coat. Skittish.”<br />
  “Looks like he’s waitin’ to be yelled at.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The vixen frowned.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Can’t say we have.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The dark fox smiled anyway.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Worth askin’.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>A raccoon came next.<br />
Then a badger.<br />
Then a pair of coyotes arguing over whether her “lung tonic” was a scam or a blessing.  </p>
<p>She played it all with the same steady ease—warm voice, quick hands, eyes always scanning the street like it owed her something.  </p>
<p>And every few minutes, the same question slid out, dressed up as idle curiosity.  </p>
<p>A fox.<br />
Quiet.<br />
Out of place.<br />
The one who didn’t bow.  </p>
<p>No one had seen him.  </p>
<p>Not today.<br />
Not yesterday.<br />
Not any day they could remember.  </p>
<p>As the sun rose and the shadows began to shrink, her patience finally snapped.  </p>
<p>She sent her last buyer away, lowered her voice to a mutter, and leaned back against the stall’s frame.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Days,” she whispered, like saying it louder might make him show up again.<br />
  “I been askin’ for days.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>How could no one know?</em>  </p>
<p>She’d seen him outside Flint Water the day after the shrine walk.<br />
Not far—near the trees, near the water.  </p>
<p>She’d followed his scent once—caught it in a quiet alley where it clung to stone and shadow.<br />
After that, the market ruined it.<br />
Too many feet. Too much noise.<br />
Everything scattered and torn apart until there was no “him” left to follow at all.  </p>
<p>That wasn’t disappearance.<br />
It was interruption.  </p>
<p><em>He hadn’t vanished that night.</em><br />
<em>He hadn’t fled like a guilty animal.</em><br />
<em>So where did he go?</em>  </p>
<p>Her gaze drifted across the street to a shuttered storefront—blank wood, sun-bleached, nothing special.<br />
But it pulled her anyway, because her mind didn’t see the boards.  </p>
<p>It saw him standing in the crowd, small and rigid while everyone else folded to the dirt.<br />
It saw the staff raised.<br />
It felt that wind again, even in memory—sharp enough to steal breath.  </p>
<p>And then his voice, quiet as confession:  </p>
<p><em>The kind that thought it was worth dying for me.</em>  </p>
<p>Her jaw tightened.<br />
She hated that it stayed with her.<br />
Hated that it didn’t sound rehearsed, or desperate, or wrong.<br />
Hated the way it left a hollow behind it—not sharp, not aching, just <em>there</em>.<br />
Like something she’d been bracing against for years had finally stopped pushing back.  </p>
<p>She wanted answers.<br />
She wanted to see him again.  </p>
<p>Not here.  </p>
<p>Not with the street pressing in and listening for sport.  </p>
<p>Her jaw set as the memory of the lake rose uninvited—<br />
the way she’d turned first,<br />
the way she’d left the question hanging because it had been easier than staying.  </p>
<p>She realized she’d already chosen, whether she meant to or not.  </p>
<p>Her breath escaped her through her teeth.  </p>
<p><em>Maybe he really is gone.</em>  </p>
<hr />
<p>A movement down the street caught her attention.  </p>
<p>A coyote—spotted coat, familiar posture, the kind of stride that said <em>capable</em> without needing to prove it.  </p>
<p>Snout.  </p>
<p>The dark fox went still.  </p>
<p>Not stiff.<br />
Not startled.  </p>
<p>Alert.  </p>
<p>Her tail slowed.<br />
Her ears angled just enough to listen harder.  </p>
<p><em>Is she here because of him?</em>  </p>
<p>The thought flashed hot and unwelcome through her.<br />
If Snout was here, then maybe Eli was too—or maybe she was just seeing threats where she wanted them.  </p>
<p>Either way, this wasn’t nothing.  </p>
<p>Snout drew closer without looking at the stall, like she meant to pass straight by.  </p>
<p>The dark fox couldn’t let that happen.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Oi,” she called, voice sharper than it had been with any customer all morning.<br />
  “Didn’t think you’d show your face in my part of town.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout stopped and turned.<br />
Her ears angled back a fraction, expression flat.  </p>
<p>She spoke calmly.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Morning, <strong>Pearl</strong>.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The name landed like a stone dropped into water.  </p>
<p>Pearl didn’t bother pretending friendliness.<br />
It slid off her like a discarded mask.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What’re you here for?” she demanded.<br />
  “Don’t tell me you’re browsin’.<br />
  You don’t browse.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout’s gaze held steady.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What I’m here for is none of your business.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pearl’s tail lashed once behind her counter.<br />
She leaned forward, claws tapping the wood.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You here investigatin’ that fox?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout held her gaze a beat too long.<br />
No answer. No denial.<br />
Just that same guarded look settling in.  </p>
<p>Pearl’s stomach tightened.  </p>
<p>Maybe she was seeing what she feared.<br />
…But it felt an awful lot like confirmation.  </p>
<p>Pearl pressed harder, voice low and pointed.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“The one who didn’t bow,” she said.<br />
  “The one the shrine folk near split open.”<br />
  “That him? That what you’re sniffin’ for?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout’s tone sharpened to match Pearl’s.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I’m not talkin’ about him with you.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>That refusal—clean, immediate—hit Pearl like a door slammed in her face.  </p>
<p>Unease crawled up her spine.  </p>
<p>If Snout wasn’t denying it, if she wasn’t laughing it off—<br />
Then Snout <em>knew</em>.  </p>
<p>Or she was trying to know.  </p>
<p>Pearl’s eyes narrowed, searching Snout’s face, trying to read the shape of her thoughts.  </p>
<p>And finding—nothing.  </p>
<p>That was the worst part.  </p>
<p>Pearl could usually tell what people wanted.<br />
Coin. Comfort. A lie that tasted sweet.  </p>
<p>But Snout stood there unreadable, and Pearl suddenly felt like she’d stepped too close to something sharp without seeing the edge.  </p>
<p>She swallowed, keeping her voice biting so nobody would hear the fear under it.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Fine,” Pearl said.<br />
  “Keep your secrets.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout held her gaze a moment longer, then turned as if Pearl wasn’t there at all.  </p>
<p>Pearl watched her walk away down the narrow dirt street, heart tapping hard against her ribs.  </p>
<p>Because if Snout was investigating Joseph—<br />
then Pearl wasn’t the only one who thought he was dangerous.<br />
And that meant they were closer than Pearl had been to finding him.<br />
And suddenly, that meant timing mattered.  </p>
<hr />
<p>Snout continued her slow circuit of the street, paws scuffing the packed dirt, ears turning at every raised voice or clatter of crates.<br />
Back and forth. Past Pearl’s stall. Away again.<br />
Never lingering.  </p>
<p>Pearl kept working.  </p>
<p>Customers came and went—quick palms, clink of marks, murmured thanks.<br />
She smiled, nodded, wrapped jars, and she talked.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Strange thing,” she said lightly to a gray-furred badger buying salve.<br />
  “Ever see a fox go stiff as a fencepost when the shrine folk pass?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>The badger frowned. Shook his head.  </p>
<p>She wrapped the salve and kept talking, voice easy.  </p>
<p>A raccoon lingered.<br />
Pearl leaned in conspiratorially—not to him, really, but past him.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Quiet little swift fox,” she said, not lowering her voice quite enough.<br />
  “Looked like he was waitin’ for permission to breathe.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nothing. Shrugs. Blank looks.<br />
But she felt it—attention tugging at the air behind her. the way it does when someone is listening hard.  </p>
<p>Pearl let the moment stretch.  </p>
<p>Then—  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Some folks don’t belong where they’re planted,” her voice carrying just enough to travel.<br />
  “And when they don’t, someone always decides what to do with ’em.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Foot steps stopped.  </p>
<p>The noise of the street didn’t—but something in it shifted.<br />
A pause. A hitch.<br />
Like a held breath.  </p>
<p>Snout turned back toward the stall.  </p>
<p>Her gaze swept the counter once, then the small knot of bodies lingering there.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“If you’re done,” she said, level and unmistakable,<br />
  “move along.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>It wasn’t a shout.<br />
It didn’t need to be.  </p>
<p>The badger hesitated, then took his jar and stepped away.<br />
The raccoon followed, casting a look over his shoulder before melting back into the stream of foot traffic.  </p>
<p>Space opened between the stall and the street.  </p>
<p>Only then did Snout step closer.<br />
Close enough for Pearl to catch her scent—<br />
—coyote musk beneath travel-worn leather, old campfire smoke ground into cloth.<br />
Wolf, too. Otter. And fox—light, fresh, threaded through the rest like it hadn’t learned how to stand on its own yet.  </p>
<p>Snout leaned in—claiming the ground.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“What are you doing?” She asked, voice low.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pearl blinked, all wide-eyed honesty.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Sellin’ remedies,” she said.<br />
  “Same as always.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout’s gaze didn’t move.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“You’re fishing.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pearl tilted her head. Smiled.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Funny. I was thinkin’ the same about you.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>For a beat, neither spoke.  </p>
<p>Then something clicked—quiet, sharp.<br />
That fox-scent threaded that through the rest.<br />
Too light. Too recent.  </p>
<p>She almost dismissed it.  </p>
<p>Almost.  </p>
<p>Snout’s jaw tightened.<br />
Whatever answer she might’ve given stayed put.<br />
She turned away instead, shoulders stiff, and resumed her patrol without another word.  </p>
<p>Pearl watched her go.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Say hello to the lil' fox for me,” she called after her, sweet as honey.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout paused for just a breath—then kept walking.  </p>
<p>Pearl’s heart hammered—fast and uneven now, the pleasure gone.  </p>
<p>By the time Snout disappeared into the press of the street, Pearl knew better.  </p>
<p>He wasn’t gone.  </p>
<p>He was caught.  </p>
<p>And she couldn’t tell if that meant silenced, delivered…<br />
or kept.  </p>
<hr />
<p>Snout kept moving.  </p>
<p>The street between Faint Line and Main never truly quieted—just shifted moods as the day wore on.<br />
Morning brought the practical rush: baskets, bundles, voices clipped by work.<br />
By noon the traffic thinned into a steady trickle, and the air thickened with heat and the smells it pulled up from packed dirt and old wood.  </p>
<p>She walked her route the way Fight had been taught to walk his—<br />
—eyes up, ears turning, attention spread wide enough to catch the small wrong things.  </p>
<p>A merchant arguing too loudly.<br />
A child trailing too close to a stranger’s tail.<br />
A pair of coyotes posting up where they didn’t need to be.  </p>
<p>And always, in the corner of her vision, the black fox at her stall.  </p>
<p>Pearl.  </p>
<p>After the exchange, the fox’s bite seemed to dull.<br />
The sharp questions stopped.<br />
The baiting remarks softened into plain sales-talk. Marks clinked. Jars changed paws.<br />
Her tail no longer snapped like a whip each time Snout passed.  </p>
<p>Snout couldn’t decide if that was relief or the kind of quiet that meant a trap had already been set.  </p>
<p>She stayed on her circuit anyway. Back and forth, never lingering, never giving the street the satisfaction of seeing her tired.  </p>
<p>Near fourth bell, her contact finally appeared—a stocky badger with a leather satchel and a bored expression.<br />
They spoke beside a shuttered doorway, quick and low: confirmation of hours, payment, nothing unexpected.<br />
He handed over a small pouch of marks that felt too light for a whole day’s work, and Snout tucked it away without comment.  </p>
<p>When her patrol ended, she left Flint Water behind with the sun sinking into a warm gold haze.<br />
The fields outside town rolled quiet.<br />
The treeline welcomed her like shade after a glare.  </p>
<p>By the time she reached camp, the light was slanting.<br />
Smoke curled up from the fire pit in a thin thread, and the familiar scents of her pack settled into her chest—<br />
—wolf, otter, bobcat, and the faint, new fox-scent that still didn’t fit right.  </p>
<p>Eli met her at the edge of the clearing, red fur catching the last sun.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Back in one piece,” he said, tone almost mild.  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout dipped her head.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Same to you.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>She started to pull the report up from memory—street names, faces, small incidents that hadn’t grown teeth.  </p>
<p>Eli lifted a paw, stopping her.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Before you give your report,” he said,<br />
  “I want to know something.”<br />
  His eyes sharpened. “Have you seen shrine folk sniffing around for Joseph these past few days?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout frowned.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“No,” she said. “None.”<br />
  “Why? You expect them to?”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli’s jaw worked once, like he’d been chewing the thought for a while.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“I’ve been thinking about him,” he said, his voice lowered and careful.<br />
  “He’s having a rough time cooped up here.”<br />
  “If there’s no pressure from the shrine—then some freedom might help.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Snout’s ears twitched.  </p>
<p>Joseph’s dull eyes flashed in her mind.<br />
The way he’d said <em>home</em> like it was a place you could bleed out from missing.  </p>
<p>And then Pearl’s voice—sweet as honey when it wanted to be.  </p>
<p><em>Say hello to the lil fox for me.</em>  </p>
<p>Snout held her face still.  </p>
<p>Pearl had been probing.<br />
Not enough to name as trouble, not enough to justify dragging Joseph deeper into the cage Eli had built around him.<br />
And Snout could not stomach being the one to tighten it further—not when Joseph already looked like he was surviving on breakfast and habit.  </p>
<p>It hadn’t been anything of note.<br />
That was what she told herself.  </p>
<p>She exhaled.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Patrol was quiet,” she said. “Uneventful.”<br />
  “No fights. No shrine folk. No one causing trouble.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Eli studied her for a beat, as if weighing the shape of her words. Then he nodded once.  </p>
<blockquote>
  <p>“Good.”  </p>
</blockquote>
<p>He turned back toward camp, already shifting his attention elsewhere—pack straps, maps, whatever kept the group alive.  </p>
<p>Snout stood a moment longer at the clearing’s edge, the mark pouch heavy against her hip in a way coin never was.  </p>
<p>She listened to the crackle of the fire.<br />
To the soft movement of the others.<br />
To the world pretending it was simple.  </p>
<p>And hoped—quietly, stubbornly—that she’d made the right choice.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Blaze the Star</name>
            <email>startheblaze@gmail.com</email>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>